各位好嗎?
(主席)
Hello everyone, it's great to be here. Thank you for the invitation, Clarence. I am really looking forward to sharing with you from Revelation.
Let me pray.
(主席)
Heavenly Father, we thank you for your word and thank you that you speak to us.
Please give us wisdom as we seek to know you more deeply.
(主席)
Amen.
On the way in today, you would have received a piece of a puzzle.
(主席)
Now can you tell from your small piece what the big picture is?
Raise your hand if you know what the puzzle is.
(主席)
Raise your hand if you have a little idea.
Anyone? Look at your neighbour's piece. Can you tell together?
(主席)
I'll give you a hint. It's a map.
With lots of ocean.
(主席)
No, that's a good guess. It's a map of New Zealand.
There you go. You have a little piece of it.
(主席)
See, when you see the box, you have the whole picture and it's easy to know what it is.
Now many people read Revelation a bit like a puzzle.
(主席)
People take the pieces of Revelation, they put it together and they try to make sense of it and guess and translate and make theories and speculations and those sorts of guesses.
But the book of Revelation is actually the whole picture of the Bible, not a piece of the puzzle.
(主席)
Revelation gives us a picture of the whole Bible, past, present and future.
And it gives us a picture of the spiritual and the physical world together.
(主席)
It's difficult for our eyes to take it all in at once, so it's a book we need to read in the context of the whole Bible and the context of the past, present and future.
And the word Revelation comes from the Greek word Apocalypse which simply means unveiling or revealing.
(主席)
And Revelation is the unveiling of the whole picture, the picture on the box.
So verse 1 says, thanks Clarence.
(主席)
So God wants us to see what will happen in the context of what has happened and what is happening now.
And so we are encouraged in verse 3 with these words.
(主席)
I won't get you to translate that your senior pastor is very fat because of pizza. But I like my favorite is not supreme. Supreme pizza is called supreme because it has everything on it.
But its not supreme. When I was at college my wife and I lived in Marrickville and there was an Italian pizza shop there that was fantastic.
(主席)
And they made not just pizza they made this thing called calzone. I am just introducing a third language here. Maybe you can say it calzone. Can you say it calzone.
It's better than pizza. It is supreme. It's like a pizza folded in half filled with cheese and lots of flavors.
If you don't like pizza you must try calzone. In my opinion it is supreme. It is the best.
(主席)
What I want us to think about today is what is supreme in your life.
What is over everything. What is the best. What is supreme. Because it is easy to read revelation thinking what is going to happen next. The world is ending. Fire and brimstone. But it is actually much more than that.
(主席)
Revelation is a matter for our hearts.
We are told to take to heart what we hear.
(主席)
And this is the thing I really like us to take to heart. Who is supreme over your life.
Last time we finished reading Daniel which the second half is an apocalyptic book like revelation about the end times.
(主席)
And we read in Daniel about kingdom after kingdom rising and falling and rising and falling. Israel, Babylon, Media, Persia, Greece, Rome. Every supreme kingdom is not supreme.
And now as we read revelation the people of God are facing a very similar situation to Daniel and this is the time of Roman emperors like Domitian.
(主席)
The mission was awful. He crucified the bishop of Jerusalem and he boiled Christians in oil.
Just like the time of Daniel this was a terrible time for God's people. People were told, were made, ordered to worship the emperor.
(主席)
And you might remember Daniel 6 when everyone had to bow down to the statue made by Darius and Daniel ended up in the lion's den.
And so like Daniel and like the first century Christians we also need to think who do I bow down to?
(主席)
Because what the rest of these opening verses of revelation tell us is that there is only one who is supreme and the whole book of revelation keeps pointing us back to him.
Past, present and future Jesus is the supreme king over all as we see in verses 4 and 8.
(主席)